<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"
                    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
  <bookinfo>
    <title>Exit 66 Jukebox Documentation</title>
    <author><firstname>Andrew</firstname><surname>Barilla</surname></author>
    <copyright><year>2001-2011</year><holder>Andrew Barilla</holder></copyright>
  </bookinfo>

  <chapter id="ch_introduction">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <sect1 id="whatis">
      <title>What Is Exit 66 Jukebox?</title>
      <para>Exit 66 Jukebox is a program to organize and play your MP3 
        audio files and functions much as a jukebox in your favorite 
        drinking establishment might.</para>
      <para>Exit 66 Jukebox runs on a single machine on your network
        which handles organizing your audio files while playing them through
		each client.  Since Exit 66 Jukebox is a webserver, any machine on 
		your network can then access it by going to http://&lt;servername&gt;/.</para>
      <para><emphasis>Note: Throughout this manual, the computer that Exit 66
          Jukebox is running on will be called 'the server.'</emphasis></para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="contactus">
      <title>How To Contact Us</title>
      <para>For technical support or to notify us of features you would 
        like to see in upcoming versions of Exit 66 Jukebox, visit us 
        on the web at <link>http://www.exit66.com/</link>.</para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="accessweb">
      <title>Accessing Via A Webbrowser</title>
      <para>All access to Exit 66 Jukebox is through a webbrowser.  To
        access Exit 66 Jukebox from the same machine as which it is
        installed on simply type http://localhost/ or http://127.0.0.1/ into
        your webbrowser.</para>
      <para>To access Exit 66 Jukebox from another machine on your network, 
        you must access Jukebox by typing http://&lt;server's IP address&gt;
        in the browser.  To find out your machine's IP address do the following
        from Windows 7/Vista/XP.</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>Select 'Run' from the Start Menu.</listitem>
        <listitem>Type cmd and press enter.</listitem>
        <listitem>Once the command line appears type ipconfig.</listitem>
        <listitem>Your IP Address will appear on the screen.</listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>You may be able to enter http://&lt;servername&gt;/ depending 
        on your networking setup.</para>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>

  <chapter id="ch_gettingstarted"> 
    <title>Getting Started</title>

    <sect1 id="firsttime">
      <title>Running For The First Time</title>
      <para>If the software is not already running, start it up now.  There
        is no standard windows interface for Exit 66 Jukebox as all
        access to it is through a webbrowser.</para>
      <para>On the same machine that you installed Exit 66 Jukebox on, start
        up your favorite webbrowser and go to http://localhost/;.  To find
        out more about how to access the Jukebox through your webbrowser, 
        please see <xref linkend="accessweb" />.</para>
      <para>The first thing you will have to do is administer the Jukebox
        server.  To enter admin mode click on the Gear button in the upper 
		right portion of the webpage.</para>
      <inlinegraphic fileref="switchadmin.jpg"></inlinegraphic>
    </sect1>
    
    <sect1 id="basicadmin">
      <title>Basic Administration</title>
      <para>All the MP3 files that Exit 66 Jukebox has access to are through
        libraries.  A library is simply a local (to the server) path such
        as <emphasis>C:\My Music</emphasis> or a network path such as
        <emphasis>\\MyServer\Audio</emphasis>.  If the directory of MP3 files
        is moved somewhere else one only needs to repoint the library to
        the new location.  No rescanning of MP3 files is needed.</para>

      <inlinegraphic fileref="admin_library.jpg"></inlinegraphic>

      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>Enter the path to your MP3 files (i.e.: 
          C:\My Music) in the "New Library" field</listitem>
        <listitem>Press 'Add'</listitem>
        <listitem>Exit 66 Jukebox has now added this path as a library
          and will scan for MP3 files and read the ID3 tags in as information
          to display.  If an MP3 file does not have a valid ID3 tag it will 
          be ignored.  Depending on the speed of your computer and the amount 
          of MP3 files this will take awhile.  If there is a problem and the
          process of scanning fails, you can try again from the
          Library screen by selecting 'Scan' next to a library.</listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>  
    <title>Using Exit 66 Jukebox</title>

    <sect1>
      <title>Main Screen</title>
      <para>The main user screen is the first thing you will see when you
        initially access Exit 66 Jukebox.</para>
      
      <inlinegraphic fileref="mainuser.jpg"></inlinegraphic>

      <para>Across the top of the screen are quick jump links to browse your
	  music files by Artist, Album or Song.  Additionally you can search through
	  all your music files.</para>
      
      <para>Next to those buttons is a status area which states the song and 
        artist that is currently playing.</para>
      
      <para>This header bar is constant and will not move as you
        browse through the Jukebox.</para>
      
      <para>Simply scroll through the list or artists, albums, songs or search results
	  and the Jukebox will dynamically load more results as you go.  This allows
	  you to have a very music library without slowing down the Jukebox.</para>
      
      <para>Once you click on an artist their songs and albums will appear.  
	  Below the album name a buttom will appear to play the entire album.</para>
      
      <para>Clicking on a song title will request the song and Exit 66 Jukebox 
		will play your song as soon as possible.</para>
      
      <para>Exit 66 JukeBox will pull a cover image from an ID3 v2 tag.  
        If you would like more information on how to do this, please visit
        our website at <link>http://www.exit66.com/</link>.</para>
    </sect1>
    
    <sect1>
      <title>Search Screen</title>
      <para>The search mechanism is used to search through all of the
        artist names, album names and track titles in the entire
        database.</para>
        
      <inlinegraphic fileref="mainsearch.jpg"></inlinegraphic>

      <para>To bring up the search results, simply type a search term into
        the search box at the top of the page and click 'Search.'  The 
        results will appear on the screen.</para>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Administration Screens</title>

    <sect1>
      <title>Library Section</title>
      <para>The Library Section is used to add new libraries, or scan or delete
        existing libraries.</para>

      <para>Scanning a library should be done if you need Exit 66 Jukebox
        to search through that path again to find new MP3 files or refresh
        ID3 information.</para>
 
      <inlinegraphic fileref="admin_library.jpg"></inlinegraphic>
    </sect1>
  </chapter>
  
  <glossary>
    <title>Options File</title>
    <para>There is a options file in the installation directory
      (c:\program files\exit 66 jukebox by default) which contains 
      settings available for you to change.  All the options are
      stored in the format &lt;options name&gt;=&lt;value&gt;</para>
    <glossentry><glossterm>webserverport</glossterm> 
      <glossdef>
        <para>The port used by the webserver.  Typically webserver's run 
          on port 80 and web browsers assume this.  For example, 
          http://www.exit66.com/ is the same as http://www.exit66.com:80/.
          Default: 80
        </para>
      </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry><glossterm>datadirectory</glossterm> 
      <glossdef>
        <para>The directory where the music information is stored.
        Default: &lt;application path&gt;\data</para>
      </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry><glossterm>databaseversion</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
        <para>Internal Use Only.  Don't touch unless instructed to
          by technical support
        </para>
      </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry><glossterm>scanthreadcount</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
        <para>Number of concurrent scans done by the software when scanning 
          a library for mp3 files.  If your machine is running extremely 
          slow while scanning libraries you can decrease this to a
          minimum of 1.
          Default: 5</para>
      </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry><glossterm>variousartist</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
        <para>The label to use for the artist of a compilation.
          Default: Various Artists</para>
      </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry><glossterm>historycount</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
        <para>The number of songs back to check in all songs played (whether
          through a playlist or request) for whether a song has been played 
          previously or not to eliminate the same song playing twice to soon.
          Default: 0</para>
      </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry><glossterm>ignorealpha</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
        <para>Comma-delimited list of words to ignore when alphabetizing
          artists names.
          Default: the,el,la,los,las,le,les,die,das,der</para>
      </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry><glossterm>defaultfile</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
        <para>Default filename to look for if none is specified.  For 
          example, http://localhost/ will look for 
          http://localhost/index.html.
          Default: index.html</para>
      </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry><glossterm>randomcount</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
        <para>Number of most recent requests in the queue to randomly pick 
          from when choosing which song to play.  Setting this to 1 will 
          always play songs in the order in which they are requested.
          Default: 0</para>
      </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry><glossterm>webdirectory</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
        <para>Location of the web templates.
        Default: &lt;application path&gt;\web</para>
      </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry><glossterm>defaultimagefile</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
        <para>Image to use when an album image can't be found in the ID3 tag.
          Default: &lt;application path&gt;\exit66jb.jpg</para>
      </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry><glossterm>unknownartist</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
        <para>Name to use when an artist can't be found in the ID3 tag.
          Default: [Unknown Artist]</para>
      </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    <glossentry><glossterm>unknownalbum</glossterm>
      <glossdef>
        <para>Name to use when an album can't be found in the ID3 tag.
          Default: [Unknown Album]</para>
      </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
  </glossary>
</book>
